We are in the era where we can just
populate in plain language a huge
document describing how something
complex should work and agent will come
up with a roughly working solution on
its own. So this is where we are in
terms of what agents can do. But again,
it's not a bug, it's a feature because
our requirements are always loose and we
are underspecifying stuff. And since we
underspecify it, the LLM has a choice to
decide on its own if the content is
underspecified, how to proceed with it.
[music]
What should I expect an agent to be
really good at most of the time and
actually not be surprised if it if it
struggles with other tasks?
>> There are lots of caveats uh to that is
that like usually it won't be exactly
what you want and you will need to
anyway like manual interventions and
fixes to validate that like fix it and
correct where it made some wrong
decisions. Uh so human in the loop still
essential if you didn't say in your
specification which database to use like
pos or it's up to the uh LLM to
come up with what it thinks but it's not
a problem of an LLM it's just because
you underspecify right so uh I would say
like to s to sum to sum up uh if you
give like a very clean instruction a
very detailed information about how you
see your solution should work uh and
what things it should include then it's
already good enough at instruction
following to develop you a prototype
which matches your expectations both in
back end and front end. I would say
[snorts]
there might be some again like
limitations of the solution which it
will come up with but that can be
because you were underspecified in the
spec or because the task was I don't
know it sometimes it can come up with
non-efficient like unefficient solution
uh which which won't be scalable and you
will anyway need to refactor but usually
it comes also because of your loose
specification so yeah like uh for sure
like in one shot in few shot you can
come up with a working game uh which
works in your browser. you can come up
with a a server which can be hosted
locally and sometimes I think you can
even go beyond that and do even a um um
you know a deployment also fully
autonomously that's what at least
lovable offers right they like fully
maintain the life cycle of the
development of a front end and back end
and serving this for you and you don't
need to you don't need to make any
decisions about this so agents are that
powerful
>> yeah absolutely and but let's now talk
about mentioning deploy deployments.
>> We're going to jump into the second half
of our conversation, but first a quick
shout out to AI Native DevCon. 2 days of
hands-on sessions, deep dives, and
honest conversations about what it means
to build AI native software November
18th and 19th in New York, or join
virtually from anywhere. Tickets and
details at a native.io/devcon.
See you there. And we think about
something that we can that we are happy
to push to production. Something that we
as professional developers now want to
want to um want to use and and and and
build with. In fact, why don't we why
don't we think first about the actual
development environment that we're that
we as professional developers need to
use. There's certain things like, you
know, security issues. For example, if
I'm if I want to use clawed code
locally, um you know, it's going to have
full access to my system. If I want to
run things locally, okay, what's
happening now? Where do I need to kind
of first of all think from a from a
professional point of view of locking
down my system a little bit more?
>> Yeah, absolutely. So, like basically if
you're uh working on your like local
version of the repo and you're given a
full access to the cloud code uh to work
on it, at some point it can do rm minus
rf uh accidentally and if you do don't
do a checkpoints, then you're in
trouble. Uh and there are lots of
stories on the Reddit where cloud code
like went that crazy and did this. Uh
and in order to you know like uh
accelerate the professional development
experience there are like different
approaches how to do that. Uh one which
you can do on your own. Yeah. You can
spawn cloud codes always in the isolated
environments. So you can uh like create
a separate docker container which will
have a replica of your repo uh and you
will you know send the commands to this
docker container and agent will in this
isolated environment will be working on
the replica and actually that's one
branch of um solving these issues with
the permissions and with a scare of
being uh of being scared to remove
something. So isolated environments
that's that's where you can um solve you
know uh some of the issues. Another type
of problem with security for example
related to the API keys for example what
if you are asking your agent to write
another agent uh right like for example
you're a company which develop develops
like agents for some reason and to test
this agent it might need to have access
to the API token right and if you
provide this API token then it can go
crazy there because it can start doing
infinite tests bas basically burning
your budget. Uh and um this this is for
these types of the you know like consu
issues that's much more hard like much
harder to come up with something some
some security solution um unless you cut
off the internet completely. Um but yeah
like that's a type of the
security concern but yeah like speaking
of the main approach the sandboxing
environments that's what um allows you
to solve most of the problems.
Another way of solving is solving these
types of problems is like again like
limiting uh the available tools for the
agents. For example, agent cannot write
uh or edit files under specific
directories. So you are as the user in
the loop can create these rules and this
will prohibit agent from making like
dangerous uh actions from uh very
sensible uh s you know like libraries uh
or directories where there's a lot of
sensitive information and yeah like some
tools for example Gemini CLI comes with
a sandbox solution available out of the
box. So if you start a Gemini session
with a sandbox from your current
directory, then it will make a clone of
your repo in the isolated docker
container and you can also specify which
commands or which tools are available.
So you can you can disconnect it from
the internet for example and then uh
yeah it will just like start working in
the isolated environment and you don't
need to do any manual spawning of the
containers. they all will be given to
you because Gemini CLI cared about this
uh and cared about this experience.
Yeah, that's uh one way to to look at
this.